Tong Ming

Phone: +86 15210955604 E-mail: tongm1987@gmail.com

Summary

Deep understanding and 4+ years hands on experience of large scale machine learning and its application on computational advertising and recommendation.

Strong programming abilities with C/C++, python. Familiar with Linux, Hadoop and Spark.

Ability to communicate effective to technical audiences in English.

Education

Master (Sep. 2009-Jun. 2012 Tsinghua University)

Bachelor (Sep. 2005-Jul.2009 Shanghai Jiao Tong University)

Experience

Senior Engineer (Apr. 2014 – Present) iQiyi Ad-backend Group(Beijing, China)

CTR prediction(solo work)

Launched the first ctr prediction system in iQiyi, which directly supports cpc advertise of iQiyi's traffic monetizing system. As the only engineer in this project, I accomplished the offline model training module and online ranking module. The system significantly increase the ctr of iQiyi's advertise. I won a third prize personally in technical and product department via this project.

Ad targeting(role: project leader of a 2-member team)

Developed a system for ad serving. The system supports various ways of targeting, including user interest targeting, content targeting, look alike targeting etc. The system boosts both the audience's experience and ctr of advertise.

Engineer (Dec. 2012 – Apr. 2014)

Douban Ad-platform Group (Beijing, China)

Ad allocation(role: member of a 2-member team)

Optimized the algorithm of offline ad allocation, and supported the smooth consumption module for online ad allocation. In order to optimize the existed offline ad allocation algorithm—high water marker(HWM), we did some experiments on getting an optimal solution of the offline ad allocation problem, also eliminating the effect of frequency capping. In all, the allocation efficiency increased by 6%.

CTR prediction(role: member of a 2-member team)

Optimize the ctr prediction for douban's ad server system. Firstly, In order to fit the data better, I tried to update the model from a linear model to a non-linear model. The new model can handle continuous feature more elegant. And the result is very inspiring, the auc of the non-linear model increased by 3%. Secondly, I tried many new features, some of them works very well and are added to the ctr prediction system.

Engineer (Jun. 2012 – Dec. 2012) Baidu EBiz Dept(Beijing, China)

Ad account optimization(role: member of a 6-member team)

Optimized the recommendation algorithm of Fengchao(Baidu's advertising business system), helping the advertisers to operate their account easier and persuading them spending more money on their advertise promotion. As a team member, my responsibility was optimizing the budget suggestion module. In order to get a better result, I analysed the advertiser behavior of setting budget and classified the advertiser into several groups by their behavior. Combined with other information(such as industry of the advertiser), the new model enhances the average budget by 21%. Because of the significantly improvement, our team received a level 3 innovation award in Ebiz Department, which is the top price in innovation award.